A Guide to the David N. Martin Papers, 1965-1998
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
David N. Martin Papers, 1965-1998
The Library of Virginia
42673
4.2 cu. ft. (12 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of David N. Martin, May 2006.
Biographical Information
David N. Martin and George Woltz founded the Martin Agency in July 1965 in Richmond, Virginia. In 1986 Martin and its partners sold the agency to Scali, McCabe, Slove, Inc. In 1988 David Martin left the Martin Agency to run Hawley Martin Partners with his brother, Stephen Martin.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1965-1998, of David N. Martin, including correspondence, memoranda, financial statements, publications, reports, and speeches relating to the Martin Agency of Richmond, Virginia.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence files, 1979-1989
Series II. Subject files, 1965-1998
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence files, 1979-1989., Extent: 11 boxes. (Box 1-11)
  Correspondence files, 1979-1989, include correspondence to and from David Martin of the Martin Agency of Richmond, Virginia. Topics include meetings and proposal outlines for potential clients, forecast of earnings, reports, advertising agreements, advertising techniques, speeches, Martin's book "Romancing the Brand", and requests for jobs. Also included is correspondence regarding changes in the Martin Agency, such as the major interest purchase of the Agency by Scali McCabe Sloves Inc., and memoranda regarding internal meetings, projects, and building of new headquarters.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1979 May - June. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1979 September - October. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1979 November - December. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1980 January. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1980 February. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1980 March. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1980 April. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1980 May. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1980 June. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Memorandum, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1982 July. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1982 August. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1982 September. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1982 October. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1982 November. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1982 December. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1983 January. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1983 February. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1983 March. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1983 April. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1983 May. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1983 June. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1983 July-August. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1983 September. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1983 October. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1983 November. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1983. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1983 December. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984 September. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1984 October-November. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1984 December. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1985 January. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1985 February. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1985 March. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1985 April. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985 May. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1985 June. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1985 July. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1985 August. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1985 September. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1985 October. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985 November. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1985 December. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1986 January. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1986 February. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1986 March. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1986 April. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1986 May. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1986 June. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1986 July. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1986 August. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1986 September. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1986 October. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1986 November. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1986 December. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1987 January. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1987 February. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1987 March. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1987 April. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1987 May. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1987 June. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1987 July. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1987 August. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1987 September. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1987 October. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1987 November. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1987 December. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1988 January. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1988 February. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1988 March. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1988 April. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1988 May. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1988 June. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1989 January. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1989 February. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1989 March. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1989 April. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1989 May. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1989 June. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1989 July. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1989 August. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1989 September. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1989 October. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1989 November. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1989 December. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Series II: Subject files, 1965-1998., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 11-12)
  Subject files, 1965-1998, including an account managers handbook, benefit plans, financial statements, publications, and speeches. Also includes memoranda, correspondence, and reports from Cargill, Wilson and Acree.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Account Managers Handbook, 1984. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Cargill, Wilson, and Acree, 1965-1967. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Long term disability plan benefits, c. 1974. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Monthly statements, 1977-1978. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Publications, Advertising: A Guide to Careers, c. 1970. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Publications, Series: What Every Young Account Representative Should Know, 1976-1978. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Publications, Series: What Every Young Account Representative Should Know, 1979-1983. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Speech material, 1994-1995. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Speeches, 1987-1989. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Speeches, 1990-1991. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, 1992-1993. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Speeches, 1995-1998. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, nd. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Speeches, Chart trade promotions, 1990-1993. (Box 12, Folder 10)